Germain Salvato Vallverdu

Associate Professor - Chemical physics and numerical simulations



10 août 1983, France Maried, 2 children

Contact

germain.vallverdu@univ-pau.fr (33) 5 59 40 78 51 (33) 6 88 59 08 87

> Technopôle Hélioparc 2 ave du Président P. Angot FR-64053 Pau cedex 9 http://iprem.univ-pau.fr

Theoretical Chemistry

Computational strategy
Development
Complex matrices
Surfaces, interfaces
VASP, CRYSTAL (solid)
Gaussian, Orca (molecule)
Gromacs, Lammps (MD)

Programming

Python Fortran, C ATEX, HTML/CSS

Languages

French English

Bibliometry

18 articles 13 conferences h-index: 8 12.5 citations per item 199 citations (181 w/o self-citations)

On the web

☐ publons 2764008
☐ GitHub ❤ GitLab: gvallverdu
☐ gsalvatovallverdu.gitlab.io

Abstract

Associate professor at the University of Pau & Pays Adour, I am a specialist in theoretical chemistry, molecular modeling and numerical simulations at IPREM institute. My research activities, in physical-chemistry, concern the understanding of macroscopic phenomena such as reactivity, thermochemistry or spectroscopy from a microscopic description of matter. The implementation and combination of relevant computational strategies allows for the investigation of complex systems in various field among petroleum-chemistry, biological systems or energy storage materials.

Professional Experiences

since 2010 Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour

Pau, France

Associate professor

Theoretical chemistry and computational approaches. Surfaces, interfaces, reactivity and molecular interactions.

2009-2010 CEA - DAM

Bruyères le châtel, France

Postdoctoral position

Development and implementation of a mesoscopic model for reactive shock waves propagation in heterogeneous systems.

2006-2009 Université Paris-Sud 11

Orsay, France

PhD Student

Theoretical study of photophysical processes in fluorescent proteins.

Education

2006-2009	PhD in chemistry speciality theoretical chemine Mention très honorable	istry Université Paris-Sud 11
2004-2006	Master degree of physical-chemistry speciality Physico-Chimie Moléculaire Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2004	Bachelor Degree of physical-chemistry Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2006	Magistère de Physico-Chimie Moléculaire	Université Paris-Sud 11 – ENS Cachan
2001-2003	Undergraduate physics and chemistry	Lycée François Arago, Perpignan

Main publications

Munoz, G. et al. Redox activity of nickel and vanadium porphyrins: a possible mechanism behind petroleum genesis and maturation? RSC Advances **2019**, 9, 9509–9516.

Santos Silva, H. et al. Impact of H-Bonds and Porphyrins on Asphaltene Aggregation As Revealed by Molecular Dynamics Simulations. Energy & Fuels **2018**, 32, 11153–11164.

Quesne-Turin, A. et al. Morphology and Surface Reactivity Relationship in the Li1+xMn2-xO4 Spinel with x = 0.05 and 0.10: A Combined First-Principle and Experimental Study. ACS Applied Materials & Interfaces **2017**,

Santos Silva, H. et al. The role of metalloporphyrins on the physical-chemical properties of petroleum fluids. Fuel **2017**, 188, 374–381.

Vallverdu, G. et al. First principle study of the surface reactivity of layered lithium oxides LiMO2 (M = Ni, Mn, Co). Surf. Sci. **2016**,

Maillet, J. B. et al. Mesoscopic simulations of shock-to-detonation transition in reactive liquid high explosive. EPL **2011**, 96, 68007.

Vallverdu, G. et al. Relation between pH, structure, and absorption spectrum of Cerulean: A study by molecular dynamics and TD DFT calculations. Proteins: Struct., Funct., Bioinf. **2010**, 78, 1040–1054.

Teaching

- Lectures in chemical-physics, theoretical chemistry and programming languages.
- Strong involvement in new information and communication technologies for education
- Science popularization: Quantum mechanics and workshops for school students